# **Bethany Fulcher**

(360) 348-8218 | fulcherbethany@gmail.com | Sultan, WA 98294

https://www.linkedin.com/in/bethany-fulcher-7a5764200/

https://github.com/bethanyfulcher

https://bethanyfulcher.github.io/updated-portfolio-page-bf/

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer with an educational background in Computer Science. Strong JavaScript and pattern recognition skills as well as an eagerness to learn new technologies and solve any problem. Recently graduated from a Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp where I worked with a team of 4 to create an award-winning MERN application that allows users to learn in a retro game-like manner.

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, Java, C#, PHP, SQL, Handlebars,

Applications: GIT/Github, Visual Studio Code, Slack, MongoDB, Robo 3t, Postman, MySQL, MySQL workbench,

Heroku

Tools: ¡Query, Materialize, Foundation, BootStrap, Jest, React, Redux, Sequelize, Express.js, Node.js,

#### **PROJECTS**

## Wizards and Whiteboards | Front-end Developer

| **Deployed Link:** <a href="https://wizards-and-whiteboards.herokuapp.com/">https://wizards-and-whiteboards.herokuapp.com/</a> | **GitHub Link:** <a href="https://github.com/vantango/htmlephant-front-end">https://github.com/vantango/htmlephant-front-end</a>

A dungeon-crawler RPG built using React.js and Redux, designed to teach basic coding concepts and provide practice for algorithm challenges to new developers seeking a fun and interactive way to implement their skills.

- Role: Heavily worked on all front-end JavaScript. Implemented a sprite for the user to move around a map and interact with other objects on said map. Worked with Redux and React components to globally change state when needed. Worked through all the game logic and debugged a majority of the project.
- **Tools**: React, Redux, React-toastify, React-ace, lodash.debounce, uuid, RPG-UI CSS framework, Axios, Express, MongoDB, Bcrypt, Cors, JWT, React-router-dom, HTML, CSS, JavaScript

## Check Your Fridge! | Full-Stack Developer

| **Deployed Link:** https://cryptic-shore-39350.herokuapp.com/ | **GitHub Link:** https://github.com/lbalbrecht/check-your-fridge

A comprehensive food catalogue for consumer use. Search up recipes based on ingredients in your fridge, save a recipe, and send your phone a text of the ingredients for your desired dish.

- Role: First dealt with front-end JavaScript then switched to back-end routes. Worked with handlebars to dynamically change the ingredients displayed. Updated the site so that the user can save a recipe to the database linked to their account and later return to if wanted. Dealt with CRUD functionality on the front-end as well as final route set-ups on the back-end.
- **Tools**: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, AJAX, Spoonacular(API), Materialize(CSS Framework), Axios, Bcrypt, dotenv, Express, Handlebars, Session, MySQL, Sequelize, Twilio

## In the Moment | Back-end Developer

| Deployed Link: <a href="https://andrew1835.github.io/In\_The\_Moment/">https://andrew1835.github.io/In\_The\_Moment/</a> | GitHub Link: <a href="https://github.com/andrew1835/In">https://github.com/andrew1835/In</a> The Moment

In the Moment is an app that allows users to search for a city and find events/breweries nearby.

- Role: Used Ticketmaster API to fetch an array of Events in a user given city and date. Fetched another array of
  breweries from Open Brewery DB API. Using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript, displayed a visual map using Google
  Maps API's and populated the locations of the previously mentioned breweries and events with color-coordinated
  markers.
- Tools: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, AJAX, Server-side APIs

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

### 2 ½ Men BBQ; Monroe, WA

Seasonal 2020-2021

#### Cashier

- Multi-tasked while going back and forth between preparing plates, making drinks, and taking orders.
- Handled the till at several events at the Evergreen Speedway.

# Fisher Scones | Conifer Specialty Foods; Monroe, WA Food Service Worker

Seasonal 2017-2019

• Contributed 12-hour shifts producing scones, overseeing the oven, and serving customers.

### **EDUCATION**

## Full Stack Web Development Certificate - University of Washington; Seattle, WA | 2021

A 12-week intensive boot camp program focused on gaining technical programming and market-driven skills.

Associate in Integrated Studies degree – Cascadia College; Bothell, WA | 2020

Accepted by the University of Washington as a transferable computer science degree.

Certificate in Computer Programming Foundations – Cascadia College; Bothell, WA | 2020

**High School Diploma** – Sultan Senior High School | 2019